Finding Aid for Records of the Bath Branch of the American Association of University Women
Elmira College
Finding Aid for Records of the Bath Branch of the American Association of University Women
1952 - 2017
The collection contains minutes, correspondence, mailings, programs and membership lists since the creation of the Bath Branch of the American Association of University Women in 1953.
3 Linear ft. (6 boxes)
American Association of University Women. New York Division. Bath Branch
Elmira College Archives, Gannett-Tripp Library, Elmira College, Elmira, N.Y.
Unrestricted
Founded in 1953, The Bath Branch is a community of people who share common interests, act on vital issues, and promote educational opportunities for women and girls. Its members have consistently been involved in community and educational activities.
Each year the Bath Branch raises money to award scholarships to local women for their college education. We also contribute to the AAUW Legal Advocacy Fund and the National AAUW Educational Foundation which is the largest source of non-governmental funding for women graduate students.
The Bath Branch has been recognized for its achievements in promoting the goals of AAUW, especially in the area of community-based programming.
Updated: September 19, 2016 [http://www.aauw-nys.org/branches/bath.htm]
minutes (administrative records); minute books; newsletters; American Association of University Women. New York Division. Bath Branch; Women’s rights—New York (State)—Steuben County; Women—Societies and Clubs—New York (State)
The collection consists of minutes, correspondence, mailings, programs and membership lists since the inception of the association in 1953. The collection primarily consists of association mailings, agendas and newsletters. The meeting minutes are incomplete and correspondence is at a minimum.
ORGANIZATIONAL NOTE:
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1: Minutes, Newsletters and published materials [1952-2017]
Series 2: Photographs [1999-2014, undated]
Series 3: Other Formats [undated]
- SERIES 1: MINUTES, NEWSLETTERS, AND PUBLISHED MATERIALS, 1952 - 2017; This series is organized chronologically and contains the yearly publications and mailings. The minutes are incomplete.
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1952-1953 -- Meeting minutes, clippings, correspondence primarily about the establishment of the Bath Branch of AAUW [1952-1953]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1954-1960 -- Programs and directories, reports, Twenty-Fifth Biennial Convention of New York State Division booklet containing reports of state chairmen and branches (1960) [1954-1960]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 19060-1964 -- Meeting minutes, 1962-64, membership list, directory and programs, conference materials, clippings, branch reports, and newsletters [1960-1964]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1964-1965 -- Directory and Program, minutes, clippings, membership list [1964-1965]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1965-1966 -- Directory and Program, minutes, conference materials [1965-1966]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1966-1968 -- Directory and Program, clippings, correspondence, minutes [1966-1968]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1968-1970 -- Program and Directories, clippings, newsletter [1968-1970]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1970-1972 -- Program and Directories, clippings [1970-1972]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1973-1979 -- Program and Directory booklets [1973-1979]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1980-1984 -- Program and Directories, clippings, newsletters, awards, membership list [1980-1984]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1984-1985 -- Program and Directory, clippings, sexual abuse pamphlet, "Names Honored" Booklet, awards, newsletters, correspondence [1984-1985]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1985-1987 -- Program and directories, clippings, correspondence, newsletters, awards [1985-1987]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1987-1996 -- Minute books, 1989-1996, Program and directories, awards, newsletters [1987-1996]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1996-1999 -- Program Directory, minutes, newsletters [1996-1999]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 1999-2001 -- Bylaws, minutes, Program directory, clippings, awards, newsletters, mailings [1999-2001]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2001-2002 -- Minutes, Reports, Program Directory, clippings, awards, Newsletters [2001-2002]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2002-2003 -- Minutes, Program Directory, clippings, awards, ledger, 1953-2003 [1953-2003]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2003-2004 -- Minutes, Program Directory, clippings, awards, newsletters, [1953-2004]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2004-2005 -- Minutes, awards, clippings, correspondence, newsletters [2004-2005]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2005-2006 -- Minutes, Program and membership directory, clippings, awards, newsletters [2005-2006]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2006-2007 -- Program and membership directory, mailings, clippings, awards, cookbook, treasurer's report [2006-2007]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2007-2008 -- Program and membership list, mailings, newsletter [2007-2008]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2009-2010 -- Program and membership directory, mailings, newsletters [2009-2010]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2010-2011 -- Program and membership directory, mailings, awards, newsletter [2010-2011]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2011-2012 -- Program and membership list, Bylaws, AAUW-NYS convention booklet, newsletters, awards, mailings [2011-2012]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2012-21013 -- Program and membership list, newsletter, awards [2012-2013]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2013-2014 -- Program and membership directory, fellowship fund ledger, reports, memos, minutes, mailing, awards [2013-2014]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2014-2015 -- Program and Membership Directory, Mailings, clippings, Congressional voting records, 2013-2014, convention materials, newsletter, clipping from 1963 about equality [1963-2015]
  - Bath Branch AAUW, 2015-2016 -- Program and Membership Directory, Bylaws, mailings, newsletters, awards [2015-2016]
- SERIES 2: PHOTOGRAPHS, 1952 - 2017; This series contains primarily 3x5 color photographs taken from 1990’s until the 2010’s and is organized chronologically.
  - Bath Branch AAUW [1999-2001]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2001-2003]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2003-2006]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2006-2007]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2007-2008]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2009-2010]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2010-2011]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2011-2012]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2012-2013]
  - Bath Branch AAUW [2013-2014]
- SERIES 3: OTHER FORMATS, 1952 - 2017; This series contains objects. The objects are arranged in order of receipt.
  - Star Pin, Undated
  - Star Pin, Undated
  - I WON 1 FOR AAUW, Undated
  - ASK ME ABOUT AAUW, Undated